redpineapplemedia.com 2018-08-17

# Privacy Policy | Red Pineapple Media

In this Privacy Policy we, Red Pineapple Media, are informing about processing of personal data and electronic communications data on our website www.redpineapplemedia.com.

Personal data includes any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person, for instance your name, telephone number, address or e-mail address. Statistical data, which we collect, for example, when you visit our website and cannot be used to establish your identity, do not fall under the notion of personal data. Electronic communications data means electronic communications content and electronic communications metadata.

### Contact Information

The controller for the processing of your personal data when you visit this website under the terms of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) is

Red Pineapple Media GmbH  
Adalbertstr. 8  
10999 Berlin  
Tel.: +49 30 6098 1841  
Fax.: +49 30 6098 1864  
E-mail: legal@redpineapplemedia.com

### Access to our website

Every time our website is used, we collect the electronic communications data which your browser automatically transmits to make your visit to the website possible. These access data comprise in particular: 

  * IP address of accessing device,
  * Date and time of access,
  * Address of the requested website and of the website requesting access,
  * Information on the browser and operating system used

The processing of these data is necessary in order to access our website and to ensure the permanent functionality and security of our systems. In addition, the access data are saved for the foregoing purposes in internal logfiles in order to compile statistical information on the use of our website, to develop our website with regard to the usage patterns of our visitors (e.g. if the proportion of mobile devices on which the pages are called up rises) and for general website administration. The legal basis is Article 6(1)(b) of the GDPR.

The information saved in the logfiles allows no direct conclusion to be drawn about you as a person – in particular, we save the IP addresses only in abbreviated, anonymised form. The logfiles are saved for 14 days and archived following subsequent anonymization.

### Data processing when you get in contact with us

You can contact us, i.e. via e-mail. In this context we process data solely for the purpose of communication with you. The legal basis is Article 6(1)(b) of the GDPR. The data which we process when you contact us are automatically erased after full processing, unless we still need to keep your enquiry for the fulfilment of contractual or legal duties (See Section: “Period of storage”).

### Register as a publisher

You have the possibility of registering as a publisher with us. For registration we store your email address and encrypted password (to facilitate login).

After registration, you can login to our publisher area where we’ll collect additional information necessary for invoicing. We have highlighted the mandatory fields. Without these data, active participation as a publisher is not possible.

The legal basis for this processing is Article 6(1)(b) of the GDPR.

### Use of cookies

For a part of our service it is necessary for us to use cookies. A cookie is a small text file which is saved by your browser on your device. Cookies are not used to execute programs or to load viruses onto your computer. Instead, the main purpose of cookies is to provide a product or service especially tailored to yourself and to make the use of our services as time-saving as possible.

We use our own cookies in particular 

  * For log-in identification

In this way we wish to enable you to use our website in a convenient and individual way. These services are based on our foregoing legitimate interest, and the legal base is Article 6(1)(f) of the GDPR

We further use cookies and comparable technologies (e.g. web beacons) of partners for analytical purposes. This is described more precisely in the following sections.

### Use of cookies and related technologies for analytical purposes

To improve our website, we use cookies and related technologies (e.g. web beacons) for the analysis of our website. The legal basis for the data processing described in the following section is Article 6(1)(f) of the GDPR, based on our legitimate interest in the needs-based design and continual optimization of our website.

The data collected include in particular 

  * The shortened IP address of your device,
  * The date and time of access,
  * The identification number of a cookie,
  * The device identification of mobile devices,
  * Technical information on the browser and the operating system

The data thus collected are saved only in pseudonymous form, however, so that no direct conclusions can be drawn about you personally.

### Google Analytics

This website uses Google Analytics, a web-analysis service provided by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“Google”). Google Analytics uses cookies and similar technologies to analyze and improve our website on the basis of your usage pattern. The data accrued in this context may be transmitted by Google for analysis to a server in the USA and stored there. Should personal data be transmitted to the USA, Google has acceded to the [EU-US Privacy Shield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/). Your IP address will be truncated prior to the analysis of usage statistics, however, so that no conclusions can be drawn about your identity. For this purpose, Google Analytics has been extended on our website to include the code “anonymizeIP”, in order to guarantee an anonymized capture of IP addresses.

Google will process the information thus gained in order to evaluate your use of the website, to assemble reports on the website activities for the website operators, and to supply further services connected with website use and internet use.

As set out above, you can configure your browser to reject cookies, or you can prevent the processing of the data generated by cookies and relating to your use of our websites in the cookie settings of Google’s Privacy Statement. Besides, you can also prevent Google from processing these data by downloading and installing the [browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de) provided by Google. Alternatively to the browser add-on or if you access our website from a mobile device, please use this opt-out link. This will prevent Google Analytics from collecting data within this website in the future (the opt-out only works in the browser and only for this domain). If you delete your cookies in this browser, you must click this link again.

You will find more detailed information on this matter in the Privacy Statement of Google Analytics.

We are deleting the analytics personal data every 14 months.

### GOOGLE reCAPTCHA

We have implemented the Invisible reCAPTCHA on our site for increased security. It's use is subject to the [Google Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) and [Terms of Use](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/terms/).

### Disclosure of data

Data which we have collected are disclosed to third parties only if: 

  * You have given an explicit declaration of consent for this, pursuant to Article 6(1)(a) of the GDPR,
  * Disclosure is necessary, pursuant to Article 6(1)(a) of the GDPR, for bringing, exercising or defending legal claims, and no reason exists to suppose that you have a predominant and properly protected interest in preventing your data from being disclosed,
  * We have a legal duty to disclose your data pursuant to Article 6(1)(c) of the GDPR, or
  * This is legally permissible and requisite, pursuant to Article 6(1)(b) of the GDPR, for the performance of contracts with yourself or to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract.

A part of the data processing may be carried out through service providers. Along with the service providers stated in this Privacy Policy, these may include in particular computer centers which store our website and databases, IT service providers which maintain our systems, and consultancy firms. Should we disclose data to our service providers, these data may only be used for performance of their tasks. We select and commission these service providers carefully. They are bound contractually to follow our instructions, have suitable technical and organizational measures for the protection of the rights of data subjects, and are monitored by ourselves on a regular basis.

Disclosure may also be made in connection with requests by government authorities, decisions of the courts and legal proceedings if it is necessary for prosecution or execution at law.

### Duration of storage

We store personal data only for as long as is necessary to fulfil contractual or statutory duties for which the data were collected. We then erase the data immediately, unless we still need these data until expiry of the statutory period of limitation for purposes of evidence in civil claims or due to statutory duties of storage.

For purposes of evidence we must still store contact data for three years from the end of the year in which business relations with you end. Any claims will expire, under the normal statutory period of limitation, no earlier than at this time.

Thereafter we must also store some of your data for purposes of book-keeping. We have an obligation to do so under statutory duties of documentation which may arise under the German Commercial Code, the German Tax Code, the German Credit and Loans Act, the German Money Laundering Act, and the German Securities Act. The periods stipulated there for storage of documents are two to ten years.

### Your rights

You have the right at any time to require us to provide information about the processing of your personal data. When providing you with this information we shall explain the data processing and supply an overview of the data relating to your person which are stored.

Should data stored with us be erroneous or no longer up-to-date, you hat the right to rectification.

Also, you have the right to erasure (right to be forgotten), i.e. if the data are no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected.

You can also have the processing of your data restricted, i.e. if you believe that the data which we have saved are not correct.

Moreover, you have the right of data portability, i.e. that we send you on request a digital copy of the personal data which you have provided.

To exercise your rights as set out here, you can communicate with the foregoing contact details at any time.

Finally you have the right to complain to the supervisory authority to which we are subject. You can exercise this right at a supervisory authority in the member country of your place of residence, of your workplace, or of the place of alleged breach. In Berlin the competent supervisory authority is: Berliner Beauftragte für Datenschutz und Informationsfreiheit, Friedrichstrasse 219, 10969 Berlin, Germany.

### Right to withdraw consent and right to object to processing

Under the GDPR you have the right at any time to withdraw any declaration of consent which has once been given. The withdrawal of consent shall not affect the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal.

You have the right to object, on grounds relating to his or her particular situation, at any time to processing of personal data concerning you which is based on Article 6(1)(f) of the GDPR.

If you wish to make use of your right to withdraw or object, a notification without set form to the contact details above will be sufficient.

### Data security

We maintain up-to-date technical measures to ensure data security, particularly for the protection of your personal data against dangers during data transmissions. To secure the personal data which you have stated on our website, we use transport layer security (TLS), which encrypts the information which you have entered.

### Amendments to Privacy Policy

We occasionally update this Privacy Policy, for instance when we revise our website or statutory or official regulations change.

Berlin, May 2018
